你们知道那种感觉吧?
You know how that go, right?
给自己定这样那样的规矩
Gave myself all these little rules about what I wouldn't do.
比如为了吸毒什么都干得出来
Like, I told myself I'd do a lot of shit to get high,
但我发誓绝不能骗毒吸
but I swore I wouldn't never trick.
但真骗了以后吧...
So, after I'm trickin'...
我想 "这也没什么嘛"
I thought, "This ain't so bad.
骗就骗了 大不了给自己定别的规矩
I'll do this for a whileexcept I'll make  some more rules for myself, like...
什么 "我一定要用避孕套"
"I'm gonna use condoms,
"一定不能和男人群交"什么的
"and I'm never gonna go with more than  one guy at the same time," and...
这么说吧 我向自己保证有些事情
Well, let's just say there are certain things I told myself
绝不会去做
I wouldn't never do.
但瘾一上来底线算什么
You know what my disease did to my rules, right?
越跟自己说不能为了毒品干的事儿
Yeah. Whatever it is you tell yourself you won't do to get high,
越是一件件干了个遍
you're pretty much making a list of everything you will do
毒瘾让你干什么你就干什么
as soon as your inner addict tells you to.
这魔障简直要害死我啊
I mean, that bitch wants to kill me.
真的
She does.
我来的路上 它还一个劲儿叫我别来
Even on my way here today, she was telling me not to come.
跟我说在大街上混有什么不好 挺好的
She was tellin' me that I was all right on the street, that it was all good.
我快说完了
I'm about done.
我想谢谢大家让我分享
I want to thank you all for letting me share.
阿门
Amen.
谢谢你和大家分享 Dee Dee
Thanks for sharing, Dee-Dee.
非常鼓舞人心
Always lift us.
今天结束得早了点
We got finished a little early.
还有人想分享一下的吗?
Anybody else feel like sharing?
你来说说 Bubs?
How about you, Bubs?
有阵子没见你发言了啊
Haven't heard from you in a while.
上去吧
Get up there!
来吧 Bubs
Come on, Bubs.
好的 Bubbles
All right, Bubbles.
嗨
Hi...
- 大家都认识我了 - 嗨 Bubs
- You know who I am. - Hey, Bubs.
Bubs Bubbles
- Bubs. Bubbles. - What's up, Bubbles?
我是个一心悔改的吸毒者
- I'm a grateful addict. - Hi, Bubbles.
到周四我就戒了15个月了
Been clean 15 months Thursday.
这是我戒毒最久一次了
This is the longest I been off.
我...
I...
我以前吸得可凶了
I used to get so high, you know.
喜欢嗨的感觉
I used to love to be high.
那时我整天在Monroe和Fayette街那块
Y'all see me out there on Monroe and Fayette
吸完毒浑身瘫软
doin' the dope-fiend lean, right?
就这样子
Be like this here.
等我清醒点 站得起来了
I come out of it, get a little more upright.
发现大家把我都当电线杆了
Realize people treatin' me like a lamppost,
往我身上贴广告什么的
hangin' fliers on me an' shit.
冬天来了小孩子把我当圣诞树 往我身上挂彩灯
Come winter, little kids hangin' Christmas balls on me like a damn tree.
夏天 他们把我抬到花园 就是现在便利店那地方
Summertime, they'd walk me over to the garden, where the 9-till-9 used to be.
把我扎成个稻草人
Make me a scarecrow.
以前执迷不悟啊
Yeah. I used to love to get high.
言归正传
Got to the point...
我觉得现在还是不太想说
You know, I'm not in the right place to talk about this right now.
下次再来吧 Bubs
Keep comin' back, Bubs.
谢谢 Bubs 感谢分享
Thanks, Bubs. Thanks for sharing.
还有其他人想说几句的吗?
Is there anybody else with a burning desire to share?
Marvin?
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
www.1000fr.net presents
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
Aruba:南美洲度假胜地
这儿又不是Aruba 婊子 - Bunk
火线重案组 第五季 第2集
The.Wire S05E02
这儿真安静
It's quiet up in here.
美国银行的账户在哪边?
You got the Bank of America accounts?
那边那堆
That pile there.
这么说
So
他声称到处筹钱 说要造篮球场养老院
he claims to be raising money for  some basketball program or day-care center.
但钱一手进 一手出
And the money comes in, and the money goes out.
篮球场和养老院却没见着
But no hoops, no day care.
假如我们抓住了Clay Davis 他也认了账...
OK, so say we get Clay Davis, and say he flips...
- 他肯定会把这事儿捅上去 - 捅给谁?
- Well, then he takes us up the ladder. - To who?
Clay只从自己的公益机构里贪污...
??If Clay is stealing from his own nonprofits...
那凭我们手上这些文件 事情倒简单了
That's an easy case for us to make with all the paperwork we got here.
板上钉钉的偷窃 也许一两桩偷税漏税
That's a straight-up theft, maybe a tax charge or two,
但这里所有证据都表明不止这些钱
but there's money that all this paperwork only hints at,
竞选财务报告上没有登记的资金
money that doesn't show up on a campaign finance report.
我猜这事儿Clay Davis也知道
My guess is that Clay Davis knows about that too.
我不知道 我还是比较喜欢实战任务
I don't know, man. I like street work more.
你宁可从早到晚坐在监视车里
You'd rather sit in a surveillance van days on end
等着抓张三卖毒品给李四?
waiting to catch Tater handing Pee Wee a vial?
同志 你是想告诉我这个吗?
This, Detective, is what you're telling me?
像这种案子
A case like this here,
你能揪出谁是重大贪污诈骗案件中的获利者
where you show who gets paid behind all the tragedy and the fraud,
你能查清不明财产来源
where you show how the money routes itself,
揭示出我们所有人如何牵扯其中?
how we're all, all of us vested, all of us complicit?
职场犯罪重案吧
Career case, huh?
能破简直死而无憾啊
Baby, I could die happy.
话说回来
Still, man,
还真不知道Marlo现在他妈在干嘛
I wonder what Marlo is up to  right fucking now.
庆祝
Celebrating.
他们还拍照么?
Yeah, but they still taking pictures?
不 我有阵子没发现了
No. I ain't feel nothing in a while.
我们干东区那票
We took care that thing over the Eastside.
他们也没抓我
They ain't on me.
Snoop这星期满地乱跑
Snoop, she been rolling around all week.
也没见小车 面包车 直升飞机
Nothing, no cars, no vans, no helicopters.
Monk进完货也查了 没问题
Monk, he checked after the re-up, no problem.
- 把他们甩了 - 那摄像头呢?
- We wore 'em down. - Well, what about cameras?
自从我们拿的那个被装回去后就没动静了
Nothing since the camera we took out the wall back at the place.
咱的夜班兄弟说一直看着呢 也没啥动静
My overnight man, he been watchin', he ain't seen nothing either.
只要咱打一枪换一个地方准没事
Sides, I think we good as long as we movin' around like this.
我看可以重新开工了
Back to bidness, I say.
她好几个月没出工了
She ain't had no work in a few months.
憋不住了
She somewhat eager.
可不是嘛
Goddamn right.
最近哪儿那么多废话
Too much fuckin' talkin' around here lately, man.
黑鬼们是时候彻底闭嘴了
Niggers need to shut the fuck up. For real.
好吧 首先
A'ight, first thing.
给Webster Franklin手下点颜色瞧瞧
We go hard at Webster Franklin's crew.
给他敬酒吃 他不要
Gave 'em the chance to get on our tit, he passed.
待我们砸了他的场子  看他服不服软
Now we bang on his corners a couple of times till he fold.
这才像话
Now you talkin'.
接下来 找那满嘴放屁的June Bug
Yeah. Next, we step to June Bug for talkin' that shit.
他一开口就他妈是死人一个了
He was a dead man when he opened his mouth.
到处晃自己还不知道
He just walkin' around not knowing it.
还有那个吹鸡巴的
An' I want that dicksucker.
拿了我的钱还满世界嚷嚷?
Took my money and the whole world know?
呸 去死吧他
Nah. He got to fall.
Omar洗手不干了
Omar rolled out in retirement and shit.
- 听说在西边什么地方 - 不干了也得把他给我揪出来
- I'm hearin' somewheres south. - Bring his ass back out of retirement.
- 好 - 行 好
- A'ight. - Yeah, a'ight.
这事儿我们去办
We can step that shit up,
找归找 他也不是吃素的
but he's goin' to be comin' at us like we comin' at him.
Joe他们都说这事儿就这么算了吧
I mean, Joe and them, they said let that be.
那小丑算什么
The crown ain't worth much
如果那黑鬼想报仇  我们就让他吃不了兜着走
if the nigger wearin' it always gettin' his shit took,
也该杀鸡给Joe看看
and Joe oughta know that.
让他尽管放马过来好了
Let him come. Yeah.
Jessup监狱那边怎么样?
What up with that thing down at Jessup?
你已经列进名单了
You on the list.
什么时候想去都行 没问题
Go on down there any time you want. No problem.
找这位兄弟
That's the dude right there.
听到没?
Ya hear?
拿钱干活的时候到了 黑鬼们
Time for y'all to earn your pay, niggers.
你讲的挺有意思啊
Funny how you started out.
- 什么意思? - 吸了毒东倒西歪什么的
- What you mean? - Dope-fiend lean and all.
怎么不说下去了?
Why didn't you keep going?
这些地方听到的怪事儿多了去了
You know, you hear a lot of funny shit in these rooms,
拿自己犯的错开玩笑 逗别人开心
people makin' fun of their mistakes, makin' people laugh,
但玩笑归玩笑
but in between all the jokes,
还是有很多真心话的
there's a lot of truth to be spoke
像今天那姑娘
Like that girl today.
说得都快掏心掏肺了吧
She damn near bled out,didn't she?
嗯
Yeah.
有一瞬间我还以为你会站出来
??For a second there, I thought you might actually stand up
谈谈Sherrod的事
and talk about Sherrod.
"一次彻底而无畏的品德检讨" 这是必要的步骤 (戒毒12步骤之第4步)
"A searching and fearless moral inventory." That's the step.
别跟我说这个 这我他妈天天干
Don't tell me about that. I live with that every fuckin' day, man.
你得说出来好让这事儿过去
You got to let it out to let it go.
我是你督导 我说你得从你脑子里出来
I'm your sponsor, and I'm telling you, you got to get out of your head,
- 从自我中出来 - 我可一次会都没缺席
- outside yourself. - I ain't never missed a meeting.
我不是在说聚会的事儿
I'm not talking about the meetings.
我说的是完了你去哪儿
I'm talking about where you go after the meetings.
我说的是你的行动 你的想法 你的感受
I'm talking about what you do, what you think, what you feel.
我没什么感受
I don't feel nothing.
这不是你的问题
That was never your problem.
就算你吸毒又低贱 这也不是问题
Not even as a low-bottom dope fiend, that was never the problem.
你现在拿这个当挡箭牌实在太可惜了
It would be a fuckin' shame to make it the problem now.
Carcetti给我们扔了根骨头
So Carcetti threw us a bone, huh?
放宽对兼职的限制了
Took the cap off secondary employment.
连我都得出去找份肥差了
Yeah. Even I may have to go out and find honest work.
在警局当差能挣几个破钱
There's no money to be made in this policing shit.
这点他们自己都说了
They made that clear enough.
你能干些啥?
What are you qualified to do?
除了这个嘛
Aside from that, I mean.
我在Friedman珠宝店找了个8点到4点的值班
You know I got an in on the eight-to-four  gig over at Friedman's Jewelry,
在Reisterstown那边
you know, off of Reisterstown.
20美元一小时呢
Yeah, 20 an hour.
穿得神气活现站着的能拿钱
Stand around with some shiny shit and get paid.
破谋杀案的倒要饿死
Work murders and starve.
这他妈什么世道?
Fuck kind of shit is that?
昨晚到今早有什么案子吗?
Anything from overnight or this morning?
有 值夜班的发现一起
Yeah, midnight shift caught one.
- 破了? - 没呢
- Solved? - Open.
Curtis海湾酒吧持械斗殴
Bar cutting from Curtis Bay.
Fahltech在停尸房呢
Fahltech's over at the morgue now.
晚上效率不高啊
Slow night.
我保证会渐渐好起来的
Oh, I'm sure things will be picking up
反正也不用监视Marlo Stanfield了嘛
now we're no longer sitting on Marlo Stanfield.
停止调查不是我的决定 Jimmy
It wasn't my call to suspend the investigation, Jimmy.
决定是你们上头下来的
That decision came from your shop.
可检察院的人谁也没反对啊?
Yeah, but nobody from the SA's office objected, did they?
就像Chris和Snoop的持枪案
Just like nobody objected when Chris and Snoop
一拖再拖也没人反对啊
got their gun charges postponed a couple of times.
一两件案子暂缓也是走程序 你懂的
A postponement or two is pro forma on Calvert Street. You know that.
走程序 还拉丁文
Pro forma, from the Latin,
是律师们互相看不惯吧
meaning lawyers jacking each other off.
规矩就是规矩 Jimmy
Rules are the rules, Jimmy.
别跟我扯什么规矩
There are no fucking rules.
都他妈在耍阴谋
Fucking game's rigged.
诸位
Gentlemen.
你干嘛跟Ronnie过不去?
Why the fuck chew on Ronnie's arm, huh?
问题又不在她
She ain't the problem
老被人耍心里烦嘛
Tired of being jerked around.
我要是找兼职
I think I'm gonna get me a secondary job
就去巴的尓摩街上的高级雪茄店
at that high-end cigar shop on Baltimore Street.
干啥? 扮印第安吉祥物?
As what? The Indian out front?
看我不把你屁股撕开花 妈的
I'd like to scalp your ass, motherfucker.
知道了
Got it.
谁去?
Who's up?
去吧 没轮到你发火时你发什么火
There you go, givin' a fuck when it ain't your turn to give a fuck.
他今天脾气不小啊
He's a pissy little bitch today.
我可真为他担心呐
I'm worried for the boy.
居然也有好消息 三年级的平均分
Some good news for a change, the test scores for third-graders
整整提高了15分
going up a good 15 points.
花了5千4百万就为了这个?
That's what I get for 54 million?
慢慢来嘛 15分是实实在在的进步
Hey, you can run on that. 15 points is a nice, solid number.
要我对考试成绩大张旗鼓
Whatever bump in the test scores I get, I got to run on it.
却不能拿犯罪率下降做竞选点?
I sure as hell can't campaign on the crime rate at this point.
Burrell已经说了不会有两位数下降
Burrell already told us we don't have a double-digit decline.
小幅下降比较有可能
A small drop, most likely.
不拿下州议会 咱们市就要饿死了
Until we take back the statehouse, this city will starve.
我去了州府 不管谁接着当市长
I get to Annapolis, and whoever I leave behind as mayor -
Bond Campbell 天知道谁
Bond, Campbell, or who knows -
就要让他们坐享其成了
they're gonna have a better time of it.
Nerese再装未来市长的话肯定没戏
It's not gonna be Nerese if she keeps goin' like she has.
太阳报把她写的很难看
Sun papers made her look bad.
她跟我说房地产跳水是 上届政府缓缴税款造成的
Yeah. She tells me this real estate flip was a holdover from the last administration.
即便是真话 她也从中捞了不少钱
True as far as it goes, but she got herself paid as well.
她的形象差到连你的选票都要拉下水
She looked bad enough that it'll cost you votes,
大家要是以为她接任你做市长
people who don't want to make you governor
肯定都不愿意选你做州长了
if that means Nerese finishes your term as mayor.
她是你的硬伤啊
She makes you vulnerable.
那我问下州长的硬伤又在哪里?
What, can I ask, makes the governor vulnerable?
他骂Olesker的样子就像个发怒的小婊子
He looked like a petulant little bitch with that diatribe on Olesker.
他也慌了嘛
He looked paranoid too.
此处系06年马里兰州州长真实事件
赌博机问题的失误呢?
What about his failure on slots?
民主党占多数席位  共和党州长吃瘪是意料中事
With a Democratic assembly, everyone expects a GOP governor will take his lumps.
再说 议会对赌博机合法化有分歧
Besides, voters are split on legalizing slots.
必须得是致命一击
It has to hit him directly.
我晚上去问问王子县的兄弟们有什么主意
Well, I'll see what's on the mind of the PG County boys tonight.
我跟Steny Miller和Maloney 要在Upper Marlboro吃晚饭
I got dinner with Steny, Miller and Maloney down in Upper Marlboro,
- 说到这个... - 你跟Jen碰头迟到了
- which reminds me... - You're late to meet Jen.
你不觉得这有点悬吗
Doesn't this seem a little thin to you,
四年市长任期 干了两年就去选州长?
running for governor two years into a four-year term?
何事不悬
Everything's thin.
全世界都指着粪便说是金子
The whole world shines shit and calls it gold.
那个Somerville不停跑去问Tommy(前市长)
So Somerville, he keeps going back to ask Tommy the elder follow-ups, right?
一个接一个问题 说是编辑叫他来问的
One question after another his editor wants him to ask him.
Somerville去敲市长的门 怪主编 （原文为主编桌)
Somerville, knocking on big Tommy's door, blaming the city desk,
"抱歉打扰您市长先生 我们主编要我问的"
saying, "I'm sorry to bother you, Mr. Mayor, but my desk wants to know."
- 我猜也猜到了 - 问了总有三四回
- Shit, I see it coming. - So, three or four times, right?
"咱主编想知道...抱歉打扰 市长先生"
"My desk is wondering... I'm sorry to bother you, Mr. Mayor,
"但我们主编要我问"
"but my desk wants to know."
最后 终于 Tommy D'Alesandro
So finally, finally, Tommy D'Alesandro,
这样把耳朵贴近办公桌 他说...
he puts his ear down to his desk like this, and he says...
"我桌子说让你的主编去死"
"My desk tells your desk to go fuck itself."
- 真事儿? - 给力就好何必计较
- That really happen? - Too good a story to check out.
我最亲爱的首席记者给他最亲爱的 编辑带回了什么好消息呀?
Hey. What's my favorite GA reporter have today for his favorite editor?
东区的悲情故事
Heartbreaker from Eastside.
育有四名子女的善良母亲 因食用青蟹过敏身亡
Salt-of-the-earth single mother of four dies from allergic reaction to blue crabs.
以前都没事 这次却在吃海鲜拼盘时昏厥
Ate them all her life but goes face down in a lump backfin platter,
一小时后于霍普金斯医院去世
pronounced an hour later at Hopkins,
她妹妹正为孩子们筹集教育资金
and the sister is starting a scholarship fund for the kids.
全家人都采访了 照片资料齐活
Interviewed the whole family. Photos, the works.
好样的
Attaboy.
再写点海鲜毒性小常识知道吗
Round it off with some medical stuff on seafood toxicity, huh?
- 危险性加剧啦 诸如此类的 - 好 没问题
- Growing incidence, all that good shit. - All right, cool.
有没有发现生四个孩子的妈特别倒霉
You ever notice how mother of four is always catching hell?
谋杀 肇事逃逸 葬身火海
Murder, hit-and-run, burned up in row-house fire,
被重婚的骗
swindled by bigamists.
生四个 不吉利
Tough gig, mother of four.
无辜路人岂不更惨
Innocent bystander is worse.
每次倒霉的都是他
He's always getting the short
现在没多少无辜路人了哟
Not a lot of them around any more.
要我说连无辜的人都少喽
Not a lot of innocence either, you ask me.
还有啥少了知道不?
You know who there's less of?
金发尤物
Statuesque blondes.
现在连报纸上都看不到金发尤物了
You don't read about statuesque blondes in the newspapers any more.
波霸女也是
Buxom ones, neither.
跟灭绝了似的
They're like a lost race.
你接着干嘛?
What do you got next?
教育专题会议
School project meeting.
Whiting先生向着普利策奖进攻
Mr. Whiting builds his Pulitzer.
今儿算是开眼界了
OK. Now I've seen everything.
怎么连的士都不叫一辆?
Why not call a cab, at least?
要是他们肯报销 我何苦不打的
If I thought these motherfuckers would reimburse me, I would have.
凶杀组不给买车吗
So Homicide can't shop cars neither.
砍得就剩俩行动小组了
We're down to two working units.
一组跟Fahlteich去了停尸房 一组刚接了新案子
One was at the morgue with Fahlteich, the other was on a fresh call.
老天啊 开什么玩笑
Jesus. What a joke.
67岁女性 育有四名子女 孙辈众多
67-year-old female, mother of four, grandmother to many,
一人独居
lived alone.
两天没见人 邻居报了警
Not seen in two days, so the neighbor called.
- 无强行闯入痕迹 - 你是第一个到现场的?
- No forced entry. - You the first officer?
踢开后门才进来的
Had to kick in the back door.
- 给鉴证科打过电话了? - 排队等着呢
- You call for crime lab? - We're on the list.
排今天的队?
Today's list?
鉴证科也他妈这样啊
Fucking crime lab too, huh?
再砍预算都砍到骨头了
They've cut everything to the bone.
估计死了两天了
Been here maybe a couple of days.
天气再热点估计就胀气了
If it was warmer, she'd have bloated.
嗯 应该是自然死亡
Yeah, it's probably natural.
就是躺那儿枕头捂着脸有点说不通
I just didn't like the way she looked laying there with the pillow and all.
嗯 我看是睡眠中死亡
Yeah, I bet she died in her sleep.
你就没早上醒来枕头盖脸上过?
You ever wake up with a pillow over your face?
有时前晚喝醉了我会扯枕头盖着脸
There's mornings with a hangover I hold the pillow over my face,
免得光一刺眼头疼得厉害
just to keep the light out and the pain down.
我嘛 吐个一两次照样去上班
Me, I just throw up once or twice and go to work.
西区光荣传统
The Western District way.
我想到一个词 "狄更斯式" (尤指类似狄更斯笔下穷苦底层社会)
The word I'm thinking about is Dickensian.
我们要刻画出城市儿童狄更斯式的生活
We want to depict the Dickensian lives of city children
并且简明扼要地指出
and then show clearly and concisely
教育系统如何辜负了他们
where the school system has failed them.
不是我替学校说话 可辜负他们的东西多着呢
Not to defend the school system, but a lot of things have failed those kids.
早在上学前他们就已边缘化了
They're marginalized long before they walk into class.
你想看这些孩子到底怎样生活
You want to look at who these kids really are,
去看看家长啊 这些孩子都没家长管
???the parenting, or lack of it, in the city.
毒品环境 社区经济情况
The drug culture, the economics of these neighborhoods.
至少学校是个打得着的靶子
Yet the schools are something that we can address.
是 都怪学校好了
Sure, we can beat up on city schools.
不隔三差五说说学校还能说谁
Lord knows they deserve to be beat on every once in a while,
但孩子的问题既不是我们造成的 也不是学校造成的
but then we're just as irrelevant to these kids as the schools are.
就好像你在屋顶一角
I mean, it's like you're up on a corner of a roof
指给人看有几片瓦片松了
and you're showing some people how a couple of shingles came loose,
与此同时 龙卷风袭击了整幢房子
and meanwhile, a hurricane wrecked the rest of the damn house.
调查学校的问题不用考虑其他情况
You don't need a lot of context to examine what goes on in one classroom.
是吗  我觉得无论调查什么都要联系现实
Really? I think you need a lot of context to seriously examine anything.
不
No.
我觉得Scott说得对
I think Scott is on the right track.
我们必须缩小范围 不被细节牵绊
We need to limit the scope, not get bogged down in details.
为了什么 为了解决问题还是得大奖?
To do what? To address the problem or to win a prize?
我们在这儿究竟干什么?
I mean, what are we doing here?
听着 Gus 情况我了解
Look, Gus, I know the problems.
我妻子在市立学校当志愿者
My wife volunteers in a city school,
但我想看到的是具体的问题
but what I want to look at is the tangible,
所有难题和解决之道必须清晰可测
where the problem and solution can be measured clearly.
学校的障碍远不止教材短缺
There's more impediments to learning than a lack of materials
或行政系统的不完善
or a dysfunctional bureaucracy.
但这有谁要看呢?
But who's going to read that?
系列报道的中心思想是什么?
What is this series about in a sentence?
预算是多少?
What's the budget line?
巧妇难为无米之炊啊
Johnny can't write 'cause Johnny doesn't have a fucking pencil.
Augustus 我并不像你想的那样头脑简单
Augustus, I'm not as simple-minded as you might think.
你要哪个 教育专题报道还是一连串借口?
Now what do you want, an educational project or a litany of excuses?
我不要那种模棱两可抨击社会的系列报道
I don't want some amorphous series detailing society's ills.
如果什么都写进去 就等于什么都没写
If you leave everything in, soon you've got nothing.
我觉得从学校下手是正确的
I think the schools are ripe for exploration,
我认为Scott可以领导这个项目
and I think Scott might be the man to lead the charge.
你他妈气死老娘我了
You ain't doin' nothin' but aggravatin' me now.
给我进屋去 看我不打烂你屁股
Get up in this house before I beat the black off your ass.
给我进去 白痴 快点
Get up in here, fool. Come on.
Treena
Treena.
Treena 等我 我马上出来
Treena. Wait for me. I'm-a come back out.
- 呆这儿别动 - 回来 丫头
- Stay right here. Don't move. - Come on, girl.
Wooton 码头报道的数据你填进去了没有?
Wooton, you dump in the numbers from the port story yet?
啊 我忘了 你要我...
Shit. I forgot. You want...
- 给我吧 我放进去 - 吞吐量比去年减少12%
- Give them to me. I'll put them in. - Overall, cargo is down by 12 points,
但滚装船比去年增加了6.4%
but roll-on, roll-off gained 6.4% last year.
好 降12 滚装上升6.4 谢谢 记下了
A'ight. Drop 12, ro-ro's up 6.4. Thanks, got it.
老板在你6点位置
Boss man on your six.
- Whiting? - 更糟 Klebanow
- Whiting? - Worse. Klebanow.
Augustus
Augustus.
明天(职棒)开赛日头条准备报道谁?
Who's the lead for opening day tomorrow?
不是体育新闻版 专题报道版的
Not the game story but the color piece.
Luxenberg想写McGuire
Luxenberg wanted to go with McGuire.
我看专题报道Scott能够胜任的
I think Scott would do an excellent job with the color piece.
我想采访些嚼烟草的老球迷
??I'd really like to find some chaw-chewing old-timer
他们宁死也不会错过开幕式
who'd die rather than miss the O's opener,
看到他们就想到棒球那种
someone who says "baseball", you know?
你说了算呗
You're the boss.
Scott 发挥你的特长
Scott, put your special touch on it,
就像去年写Preakness那篇报道一样
like you did with your Preakness piece last year.
- 祝你好运 - 谢谢
- Good luck to you. - Thanks.
我操
Fuck.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
没事儿 你继续睡吧
It's all right, go back to sleep, baby.
- 报社总台 - 喂 Spry 是我
- Metro desk. - Hey, Spry, it's me.
夜班编辑还在校对室吗?
Hey, is the night man still on the copy desk?
在啊 你有什么要改的吗?
Sure is. You need to make a change?
嗯 我就查一下港口报道
Yeah, yeah, I just want to check on the port story.
我可能有几个数字写颠倒了
I think I might have transposed some numbers.
Andy 港口报道能拿回来吗?
Andy, can I get port back?
行 可以
Yeah, sure.
还没定稿付印 说吧
We got time on the final. Go ahead.
嗯 背景介绍部分
Yeah. Somewhere down in the A-matter,
关于货运总量的百分比
a graph about the cargo trends with percentages.
- 吞吐量 滚装... - 读给我听
- Ro-ro, cargo... - Read that back to me.
吞吐量降低12% 滚装船增加6.4
Cargo down 12%, ro-ro up 6.4.
降低12点 滚装上升6.4?
12-point decrease and a 6.4 bump on the ro-ro?
对 没错
Yep, that's it.
靠
Shit.
我半夜吓醒一身汗 还觉得自己搞错了 你确定?
I woke up in a sweat 'cause I thought I'd fucked that up. You sure?
你这是常见的截稿日噩梦 虽然莫名奇妙
Tonight, you had the usual deadline nightmare to no actual purpose.
我看你比自己想的更在行了嘛
I guess you're better at this than you thought.
大概吧
Yeah, I guess.
谢了 Jay
Thanks, Jay.
不客气 晚安
Anytime. Good night.
丈夫心想 "天哪" 警察出现在他家门口
The husband's thinking, "Gosh." I mean, the police show up at his door
说到"你从乌克兰娶回的妻子"
and say, "The lady you married from the Ukraine,
"A 她已经死了  B 她有辆2005版纯金奔驰..."
"A, she's dead, B, she's got a 2005 gold Mercedes..."
我那老太太什么时候好?
How long till my old lady?
还得等会儿呢
It's gonna be a while.
我忙着呢
Got my hands full.
我去街对面吃早饭
I'm across the street for breakfast.
- 只有一种办法能判断 - 得了吧 胡扯
- There's only one way to rule. - Come on. Bullshit.
这哪是不是谋杀
This is not a murder.
是吸毒过量
He overdosed.
我们在他家浴室地板上找到吸毒工具
Look, we found his gear on the bathroom floor,
还有她女朋友打的911
and his girlfriend, who called 911,
也说他们是在吸毒
said the two of them were firing.
我还没拿到验毒报告 但就算其中含有海洛因
I don't have the tox results yet, but even if they find heroin
也只是次要死因
it'd be a secondary cause.
尸体有瘀斑 脖子周围有淤青
I've got petechials, I've got bruising around the neck.
我初步判断是谋杀 机械性窒息
My preliminary is homicide by mechanical asphyxia.
好吧
OK, fine.
我他妈这就把急救人员带过来
I'll fucking bring the paramedic in here,
让他跟你他妈亲自解释
and he'll fucking explain it to you himself.
这样行吧
Yeah, that's right.
我还要大老远跑去Dundalk把他拖过来
I'm going to go all the way out to Dundalk, drag his ass in here
好让你亲耳听他说
so you can hear it from him,
我才不信这是谋杀呢
'cause I ain't taking this as a murder.
嗨 Jimmy
Hey, Jimmy.
Nancy 最近怎样?
Hey, Nancy. How's tricks?
是听说你重回凶杀组了
Heard you were working murders again.
嗯
Yeah.
县里怎么样?
How's life in the County?
一年不如一年
Worse every year.
你们自己地盘上的事自己管不了
You guys can't keep all the dirt on your side of the line.
Kevin怎么发那么大火?
What's Kevin so hot about?
新来的法医非要逞强
Oh, new cutter's dug her heels in,
说这是谋杀
says it's a murder.
其实不是
It's not
不过她错看成勒死也不奇怪
but I can see why she'd think strangulation.
那家伙舌骨断裂 双眼都有出血点
Guy's got a fractured hyoid, petechiae in both eyes,
但成因太诡异了
But it's a freak thing.
要不是亲眼所见 我自己也不信
If we weren't there to see it, I wouldn't have believed it myself.
都是死后造成的
It's all postmortem.
他两种药一起抽 昏了过去
He fires up a speedball, then blacks out,
倒在马桶和浴缸之间
falls between toilet and bathtub,
结果卡得死死的
manages to get himself wedged back pretty good.
这事儿编都编不出来
I couldn't make this shit up.
医生到后宣布他当场死亡
Medics come, pronounce him right then and there.
但问题是 不卡住他的脖子 根本使不上力把他拔出来
But get this - they can't pry the guy out without grabbing hold of his neck for leverage.
我们亲眼看他们弄的
We watched them do it.
就是叫Dundalk的急救员和一太平间的
This Dundalk medic and the morgue guy
拉着他的脖子就往外扯
just grab his neck and start yanking.
终于把他弄出来 到这儿一看跟勒死一样
Finally they get him out, he comes down here looking like a strangle job.
无法辨别是死后造成的?
They can't tell that it's postmort?
刚死的尸体 没人分得清
On a fresh body, no one can.
抓得太重 保不齐弄出点瘀斑
Grab a guy too hard, and you can cause petechiae,
弄断舌骨
break a hyoid,
还能有乌青呢
even leave bruising,
都是死后弄的
all after death.
我操
Fuck me.
是啊 所以Infante要是无法澄清这不是谋杀
Yeah. So Infante's about to lose his mind
恐怕都要急疯了
if he can't talk this thing out of becoming a murder.
不然只能起诉急救人员
Either that or charge the paramedic.
你准备去街对面吃早饭?
You goin' across the street for breakfast?
- 请我吃肉馅饼呗 水手? - 走吧
- Buy me some scrapple, sailor? - Come on.
2号
Number two.
惊喜哦
Surprise.
我兄弟Sergei觉得我们应该先谈谈
My man Sergei thought we should talk first.
谈什么?
Talk about what?
谈你咯 小子
That's on you, young 'un.
不管你想和俄罗斯人做什么生意
Whatever business you tryin' to do through the Russians,
都得先通过我
you got to go through me first.
- 是么 - 没错
- Yeah? - Yeah.
因为在这儿 大伙都管我叫...
'Cause up in this bitch here, I'm what you might consider...
带头大哥
an authority figure.
大家都来找我帮忙 问我意见
You know, everybody got to get my help or ask my advice,
什么事儿都有
like, on all kinds of shit.
Sergei有天来找我说有个黑鬼Marlo
Sergei step to me the other day sayin' this nigger Marlo,
他认都不认识的
who he don't even know,
给他寄钱
just be sending him cash money
想加入他的访问名单
to get on his visiting list.
他就问我认不认识Marlo
So, then he ask me if I knew Marlo.
我告诉他 "当然啦 我跟Marlo可熟了"
I tell him, "Hell, yeah, I know Marlo real well."
你懂吧 在西区 大家都认识大家嘛
You know? Over Westside, everybody know everybody, right?
你不说我帮你说吧
Let me help you find your tongue.
你想找俄国佬
You tryin' to get to the Russian
是想跟他的人搭上关系
so you can get a line to his people.
从而联系上那帮希腊鬼子
You tryin' to get to the Greek motherfuckers
因为你要是成功
because if you can
就能踢开Joe老大
you want to cut Proposition Joe
绕过所有东区那帮婊子
and all them other Eastside bitches out the connect.
你做生意挺有天赋啊?
I mean, you a natural businessman, right?
但一桩归一桩
But this is the thing, though, and I mean,
你这么干我没意见 懂吧?
you know, I'm with you on all that as far as it goes, you know?
西区的兄弟们要团结一致 明白我意思吧?
Westside definitely need to stick together, you know what I mean?
你不来过问我
And all the fuss about you comin' at me -
我说过去的就让它过去吧 操他妈的东区婊子们
I say let bygones be bygones, but fuck all them Eastside bitches.
老子就是这句话
That's just the way I feel about it.
对咱西区的黑人弟兄们我心中只有爱
I got nothin' but love in my heart for Westside niggers,
光只有爱
nothin' but love.
当然啦 你懂的
Of course, I mean, you know,
也得让老子尝点甜头
I got to have my taste too.
猜到了
Figured that.
给我妹子送十万去
So send my sister a hundred large,
下次你来探监
and the next time you come to Jessup,
就不用跟我鬼扯了
it won't be my grill talkin' at you.
我保证
My word on that.
十万是吧?
A hundred large, huh?
怎么了? 不然会怎样 你明白的吧?
So what's up, man? What's up with you otherwise, you know?
游戏有游戏的规矩
The game is the game.
可不是
Always.
不可能
They do not.
- 我看你瞎掰的吧 - 我正找你呢 Jimmy
- You're making that shit up. - I'm looking for you, Jimmy.
怎么了?
Hey, what's up?
郡里的Nancy Porter你认识吧?
You know Nancy Porter from the County?
Lester Freamon
Lester Freamon.
很高兴见到你
Good to meet you.
谢谢你请我吃早饭
Well, thanks for breakfast.
一会儿楼下见
I'll see you downstairs.
我昨晚在McCulloh家门口坐了一宿
I spent last night sitting on that same McCulloh Street lot.
- 他们回去了? - 两次
- They went back there? - Twice.
天擦黑去了一次 三点后又去了次
Once in the early evening and once again after three.
他们开始马虎了 Jimmy
They're getting sloppy, Jimmy,
尤其是他们以为我们已经撤兵
especially now they think we've backed away.
安几个窃听器 两三个小监视摄像头
You know, a few good bugs, a couple of small surveillance cameras,
花点时间下去 两周 最多三周
some man hours, two weeks, three the most.
就能把他们擒拿归案了
That's all this fucking case needs.
Daniels不让我们干 他话说得很清楚了
Daniels can't give us that. He made that pretty fucking clear.
那我们另辟蹊径
Then we go elsewhere.
右翼手 21号 Nick Markakis
Right field, number 21, Nick Markakis.
去看比赛吗?
Going to the game?
老球迷了?
Long-time O's fan?
什么开塞日跟我屁关系都没有
I could care less about opening day at this point.
都赖Bud Selig和Barry Bonds 把棒球毁得差不多了
Between Bud Selig and Barry Bonds, they've ruined baseball for me.
- 能聊一分钟么? - 约了人迟到了
- You have a minute to talk? - Late to meet somebody.
还怎么专心搞体育啊
How can you commit to a sport
政府专员连封锁劳工都做得出来
where the commissioner justifies a labor lockout
还取消世界杯?
and cancels the World Series?
你做(巴的尔摩)金莺队球迷多久了?
How long you been an O's fan?
我其实从小喜欢芝加哥小熊队 我儿子比较喜欢金莺所以才...
Actually, I grew up with the Cubs, but my son, he kind of likes them so...
还服用兴奋剂 棒球好不容易剩的那点精神
And then on steroids, which has destroyed what's left of baseball's credibility,
早不知上哪儿去了
he's nowhere to be found.
你是金莺队球迷吗?
So, you an Orioles fan?
开赛日之际您是否感到激动呢...
Are you excited that it's opening day because something like that is...
操你妈棒球!
Fuck baseball!
花生哟 买花生喽
Peanuts! Get your peanuts!
51 52 53
51, 52, 53.
嗨 Bubs 你怎么样?
Hey, Bubs, how you doin'?
走到底找个位子坐下
Have a seat all the way around the other side.
多谢了您呐
Much obliged.
不许哭 别从老娘盘子里抓东西
Stop crying. Don't grab stuff off my plate.
看我不抽死你
Mommy's going to whup you.
有什么需要帮助的吗?
Do you need some help here?
咱们这儿不能乱来
Because we don't do that here.
在我们家不许打人 更不许打孩子
In our house, there's no hitting anyone, especially children.
你明白吗?
Do you understand me?
对不起我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
交通简直是噩梦
Traffic's a nightmare.
你们觉得好玩是吧?
Think you're funny, huh?
以为我没有...
Think I still don't have...
好了 知道你们厉害 妈的
All right, I get the point, fuckholes.
都去死吧
Fuck you both, already.
再过几年你们可以倒退回去玩遥控车了
A couple more years of this, you'll be ready for a radio car.
干嘛不能上我办公室来 像成年人一样办事
Why is it you can't come up to my office and do this like grown-ups?
Woodlawn那边还得在前台签到吧
They still make you sign in at the front desk out Woodlawn?
你们丫的这次又惹上谁了?
Who'd you knuckleheads piss on this time?
头头叫停的项目 我们还在撬边呢
We're still working the edges of something the bosses shut down.
- 哦 什么案子啊? - 空屋弃尸案
- Yeah, what are we talking about? - The bodies in the vacants.
那案子叫停了?
They shut that down?
乖乖 22具尸体就不算了?
Jesus Christ. What, 22 murders doesn't rate?
不算了呗
Not any more.
你们查了都快一年了
You were on it more than a year.
查到哪儿了?
Where were you?
快了 不能撒手
Too close to quit.
你认识Marlo Stanfield
You know Marlo Stanfield,
Chris Partlow和Snoop Pearson?
Chris Partlow, Snoop Pearson?
这些名字有印象
Those names ring out.
实验室没啥结果
Well, we got nothing back from any lab work,
没有目击证人 没证据起诉谋杀
there's no witnesses, nothing to make a murder prosecution,
咱就换法子
so we settled in,
暗地里盯了他们一年
sat on them for about a year.
- 了解作案模式了? - 非常清楚
- You got a pattern? - A good one.
FBI的专业监视监听盯上两三周
Two or three weeks with some good FBI cameras and wires,
派五六个探员吧...
maybe a half-dozen agents...
当初立案时我就跟你们说过
Like we tell you boys when the case broke,
我们对这种贫民区毒品案不感兴趣了
we aren't much into ghetto drug shit any more.
我们的人都在忙反恐啦政治什么的
Most of our guys are counter-terror and political stuff.
跑腿的事儿我们已经干了
We already did all the long legwork.
再干两三周 头版头条就是你们的了
Two or three weeks, you guys end up with a big headline.
你们FBI不就喜欢头条么
You federal fucks like headlines.
我先去局里问问
I'll run it up the flagpole.
- 我可开走了啊 - 行啊
- I'm gonna drive away now. - All right.
要是你们这些傻逼没意见的话
If it's OK with you two suckholes.
欢迎来到Camden体育场
Welcome back to Camden Yards.
正如刚才所说 金莺队...
As we mentioned a moment ago, the Orioles know...
有好料了
I got good stuff.
等等
Hang on.
过来告诉我 给你留着版面
Come here and tell me, so I can put it on the budget.
在体育场外找到个坐轮椅的孩子
I got a kid in a wheelchair outside the stadium,
很想去看比赛
wanting to go to the game
但是没钱买黄牛票所以看不了
but unable because he didn't have the money for a scalped ticket.
听着不错 有照片么?
Sounds pretty good. You got art?
问了 摄影师说都在赛场内忙呢
???Photo said they were too booked with the game.
这是你的专题报道
This is your main color piece.
要报道这孩子至少要有张照片啊
You got to have a picture of the kid if he's your lead.
- 现在派人去行吗? - 大概吧
- Can we send them out now? - I guess.
他可能走了 不过你可以试试
He probably rolled out, but you can try.
操
Shit.
- 这孩子多大? - 13
- How old is this fella? - 13.
他爹妈呢? 他怎么不上学?
What's with his parents? Why wasn't he in school?
在这儿上? 他刚辍学
What, in this city? He just cut.
- 那他爸妈呢? - 都死了 没人
- So what about his parents? - Both dead. No shit.
- 他跟阿姨住在巴蒂尔摩西区 - 怎么会坐上轮椅的?
- He lives with his aunt in West Baltimore. - How'd he get in the wheelchair?
中了流弹什么的 说得挺模糊的
Something about a stray gunshot. It was all pretty vague.
中枪日期有么?
You got a date when it happened?
他不太愿意和我多说啦
??He was a little hinky with telling me much.
其实他只肯告诉我他的外号
Fact is, he would only let me go with his nickname.
我得开始写了 如果你想按时要的话
Look. I got to start writing if you want it for the e-dot.
嗯 你就在公共系统上写吧 我好在一边看着
Yeah. Why don't you work in Metro Write so I can read over your shoulder?
Scott 他叫啥来着 外号?
Hey, Scott. What he go by, the nickname?
- E J - E J
- E.J. - E.J.
Jane 过来下
Hey, Jane, come here a minute.
查下过往三年资料
Check clips for the last three years.
看看有没有个被流弹射中的孩子
See if we got anything on a kid in the city wounded by a stray bullet.
现在该13岁了
He'd be 13 now.
外号叫EJ 可能是姓名缩写
Nickname of E.J. Could be his initials.
跟我们什么关系啊
Who is he to us?
是开赛日的新闻人物
He's the lead of our opening-day piece.
要是找到了 找人给他拍张照片
If we find it, I'd love to get art on the kid.
别抱太高期望
Don't hold your breath.
这案子不小啊
It's a hell of a case, really.
天地良心他们是需要帮忙
And God knows they could use the help.
- 抱歉我来晚了 - 有什么进展?
- Sorry I'm late. - Anything up?
老样子
Just the usual.
- 你还好吧? - 嗯
- You all right? - Yeah.
要是弄对了 就像螺旋梯一样
We do this right, it is like a spiral.
从圈子外围入手 在边缘逐渐突破
We start on the outside of the circle, and we work our way around the edges,
顺藤摸瓜逼近Clay和他的同党
pick up everything we can before we get to Clay and the people he keeps close.
你觉得Clay知道起诉书的事情?
You think Clay knows the indictment's coming?
Clay Davis就等着致命的最后一击呢
Clay Davis has been waiting for the other shoe to drop his whole life.
他知道
He knows.
来找我碴的是你的人
And it's your people up in my shit.
不是FBI 也不是Annapolis州里的人
Not no feds, not no state people from Annapolis.
他妈的都是自家后院的人
It's motherfuckers from my own city.
我也无能为力啊 Clayton
My hands are tied here, Clayton.
现在是新市长 新的州检察官
It's a new mayor, a new state's attorney.
在外替你卖命的可是我 你知道的
I'm out there doing the Lord's work for you, Erv. You know it.
谁去市议院争取到加薪的?
Who got that pay raise through the council?
给你家换新院子够了
Just enough for you to get that new patio
让匹兹堡那家伙接替你不够是吧
but not enough for that guy from Pittsburgh to take your place.
我也想帮你的嘛
I wish I could.
你知道我想的嘛
You know I wish I could,
但是Carcetti上任 大家都看着嘛
but with Carcetti in, people are watching.
我也在众目睽睽之下嘛
I got eyes on me now.
你好歹还是局长吧?
You the commissioner still, right?
是 但现在跟以前不一样
Yeah, but it ain't like it was.
靠 那你不管谁管?
??If you don't control it, who does?
这件事 我得避开Daniels
On this, I got to reach around Daniels,
他是Carcetti的人
and he's Carcetti's boy.
这可是大陪审团的调查啊 拜托
Look. This is a grand jury investigation, for God's sake.
咱俩没准都被起诉妨碍司法公正
We could both be charged with obstruction of justice.
你姥姥的 Erv
God damn it, Erv.
我为你瞻前马后任劳任怨  你就这么报答我?
I been there for you, carried water for you, and you do me like this?
Clay 我没法子 没人可以
Clay, I can't. Nobody could.
你觉得我死定了是吧?
You think I'm goin' down, don't you?
你看准我死定了
You think I'm done.
你们这些忘恩负义的婊子们 都想着过河拆桥
All y'all ungrateful bitches thinkin' you can throw me out the boat.
- Clay - 好!
- Clay. - A'ight!
这场面我记着 Erv
I'm gonna remember this moment, Erv.
我得牢牢记着今时今日
I'm gonna hold on to this moment.
呸
Yeah.
Clay来找你哭?
Clay crying to you?
好像我理得清这团乱麻似的
Like I could put brakes on this mess.
这是...
Is that...
嗯 刚从审计局拿来
Yeah. Straight from P and R.
数字已经改到不敢再改的地步了
And that's with the numbers bent as far as we dare.
市政厅要求真实数字嘛
With city hall asking for clean stats,
我们也只能兵来将挡
there's only so much we can do.
我们该怎么告诉市长?
The hell are we gonna tell the mayor?
我坐那儿跟他和他的部下谈了半小时
I sat there for half an hour with him and his deputy.
他明白事态严重性
He knows what he's saying no to.
- 那他妈怎么还... - 是私仇 Jimmy
- Then how the fuck... - It's personal, Jimmy.
市政厅有人惹了州检察官了
Somebody at city hall really pissed off the US Attorney.
你开玩笑呢吧
You're kidding me.
不 我亲耳所闻
No, and I got an earful.
你跟Lester说我还在想办法看怎么弄
You tell Lester I'm still trying to figure out what the problem is,
不过眼下
but for right now,
这案子你是别想推出去了
you forget about shopping this case anywhere.
毒品管理局 烟酒枪支局 海关 全国都把你们给封杀了
DEA, ATF, Customs - you guys are shut out across the board.
神仙下凡也就不了你了
Fish and fucking Wildlife couldn't help you.
抱歉 兄弟
Sorry, brother.
这孩子哪儿都找不到
The kid is nowhere to be found.
我让摄影师去挖 也没结果
I sent photo down there to try to dig him up. Nothing.
- 可能走了吧 - 好
- Probably left. - OK.
你说一个坐轮椅的黑人穷孩子没票
So we got a poor black kid in a wheelchair with no ticket.
一路摇着轮椅从巴的尓摩西区来到...
He rolls himself from somewhere in West Baltimore to...
来到"以金莺公园著称的 宏伟砖砌体育场的阴影中
to "the shadow of the mighty  brick-faced coliseum known as Oriole Park,
"听着场内观众的欢呼来了解比赛情况"
"listening to the cheers from the crowd, which told the whole tale."
这得好好查查啊 一13岁娃 只知道叫EJ
W-We're gonna give good play to a 13-year-old known only as E. J,
逃课出来 不敢报真名
who declines to give his name because he skipped school,
没爹没娘 跟阿姨住在一起
he's got no parents, he lives with his aunt.
我不是说你写的这孩子有什么不实之处
I mean, I'm not saying that this kid isn't everything you say he is,
但Scott 靠 作为你的编辑
but, Scott, damn, as an editor,
要把这发出去怎么也得多点细节吧
I need a little more to go on if I'm gonna fly this thing.
我不喜欢你的暗示
I resent the implication.
我没有暗示什么 我跟你是一边的
I'm not implying anything. I'm on your side.
但我们的标准总得...
But the standard for us has to be...
Scott 你接着写完吧
Scott, just finished your story.
好文笔 我给你登头版
Good read. I'm putting it out front.
你完全抓住了城市两个不同群体间的反差
I think you've really captured the disparity of the two worlds in this city
行文紧凑流畅
in a highly readable narrative.
我看一字都不用改了
I wouldn't change a word.
多谢 只怕有人不像您这样看好我
Thanks, but I'm not sure everyone shares your enthusiasm.
Jim 难道你就一点也不担心
Jim, aren't you just a little bit concerned
我们连这孩子姓什么都不知道?
that we don't even have a last name for this kid?
我们报社不是一向以...
I thought we held ourselves up to a...
情况是不理想
It's not an ideal situation, no,
但这孩子不肯说出姓名
but the boy's reluctance to give his last name
显然是因为害怕逃课被抓嘛
clearly stems from his fear of  being discovered as a truant.
你有什么问题吗?
You have a problem with it?
有点吧
yeah,A little bit, yeah.
我只是觉得按一贯的标准...
I'm just saying that the standards that...
我看此事就这么定了吧
I think we're on terra firma here.
明白了
Gotcha.
老板发话了 你接着写吧
The man made a call. You're good to go.
谢了 Scott
Thanks, Scott.
那儿就是黑鬼Webster的店
The nigger Webster's shop right there.
这样 我开过去 你们速度下车速度动手
So look, I'm gonna roll up, and y'all gonna pop out and pop off.
能打多少打多少
Drop who you can.
喂
Yo.
咱按西岸的规矩来吧
Let's go all West Coast with this.
说啥呢?
Say what?
一直开
Drive-by.
他们都这么来的
That's how they do.
放倒敌人 但毫不减速
Drop a motherfucker and not slow down.
像"邻家少年杀人事件"那样
Like Boyz N The Hood.
酷毙了 记得吧?
Shit was tight, remember?
- 给你 - 哥儿好啊?
- Yo, there you go. - What's up?
妈的 我他妈一个都没打着
Man, I ain't even hit near one of them.
这黑鬼受伤了
This nigger's wound.
西岸的黑鬼都他妈去死吧
Fuck them West Coast niggers,
咱巴市的规矩 指一个打一个 记住喽
'cause in B-more,we aim to hit a nigger, you heard.
那家伙在市里各处抛了二十几具尸体
Guy leaves two dozen bodies scattered all over the city,
竟然他妈没人管
no one gives a fuck.
你看他杀的都是谁
It's because who he dropped.
那倒是
True that.
这国家杀黑人向来没人管啊
You can go a long way in this country killing black folk.
尤其是年轻男性
Young males especially.
次要谋杀案
Misdemeanor homicides.
要是Marlo杀的是白种女性
If Marlo was killing white women.
白种儿童
White children.
游客
Tourists.
一名曾为拉拉队员的白人游客在Aruba失踪
One white ex-cheerleader tourist missing in Aruba.
问题是 这儿不是Aruba 婊子们
Trouble is, this ain't Aruba, bitch.
要是这市里一年300个白人被害
You think that if 300 white people were killed in this city every year,
他们还不赶紧派82空降师过来?
they wouldn't send the 82nd Airborne?
黑人嘛
Negro, please.
肯定有啥法子让他们开绿灯
There's got to be some way to make them turn on the faucet.
喂 Jimmy 这儿就数你脑子灵光
Come on, Jimmy. You're the smartest boy in the room.
你倒是替这倒霉城市想想办法
You come up with something in this broke-ass city.
他结婚了还怎么着
Isn't he married or some shit now?
这篇开赛日报道你审的?
Did you edit this opening-day piece?
Whiting亲自拍板一字不改 我连挥刀下手都来不及啊
Whiting himself blessed it as written before I could take a meat ax to it.
这孩子连全名都没有你没意见?
Did it bother you that we don't have the boy's full name?
有 Rebecca 意见大着呢
Yes, Rebecca, it did.
你别"哼"我
Don't give me that "huh".
我说什么Whiting都不听
Whiting wasn't buying any problem I had.
连照片都没有?
No art of the kid?
没有
None.
我们在这多久了?
How long we been here?
一个多小时了
More than a hour.
你说咱干嘛要坐这儿?
Why you think we sitting here?
看谁回家了谁没回
See who home and who not
谁站岗放哨
who on the block
有没有条子啥的
police and whatnot.
没错
That's right.
绝对不能最后一刻才到现场
You don't ever want to be the last man to a party.
明白吗?
You feel me?
所以我出任务都提前一个钟头
That's why I show up to a job an hour before.
有时甚至俩钟头
Sometimes two.
螳螂捕蝉 要确保没有黄雀在后
I don't want nobody settin' up on me while I'm settin' up on them.
干他妈这行的
'Cause there ain't no good thing about
要出岔子准不是啥好事
motherfuckin' surprises in this line of work.
我们干嘛要办了June Bug?
Why we doin' June Bug anyway?
他管Marlo叫基佬
Heard he called Marlo a dicksuck.
说些这个那个的
Talkin' shit like that.
你听说的? 你也不确定?
You heard? You ain't sure?
有人说是他说的呗
People say he said it.
到底说没说过不重要
Don't matter if he said it or not.
大家以为他说了
People think he said it.
这事儿不能这么完了
Can't let that shit go.
为啥?
Why not?
Marlo又不是真的搅基 是吧?
I mean, Marlo ain't suck no dick, right?
要是Marlo知道自己不是基佬
So, if Marlo knows he ain't suck dick
他管June Bug胡咧咧什么啊?
then what the fuck he care what June Bug say?
管别人怎么说啊?
What anybody say?
这家伙胡扯几句就得死?
Why this boy got to get dead just for talking shit?
谁叫他满嘴放屁 活该
'Cause he got a big motherfuckin'mouth, that's why
你自己的嘴也给我管住了 小子
and you need to stop runnin'your own mouth, young 'un.
来了
There it is.
带的打手也都齐了
And all the muscle he got.
- 看见了? - 准备好了?
- See it? - You ready?
你干掉那家伙
Now you handle that thing.
给我个信号 咱在大门口见
You give me a sign, meet me out front.
Michael 你绕到巷子后面去
Michael, you go round the alley.
要是有人从后面逃 你就毙了他
Body come bustin' out the back, you drop that shit.
我操
Shitfuck.
平时喝吐的不都是Bunk么
Bunk's usually the one throwing up.
吃过阿司匹林了?
You took aspirin?
六粒
Six.
那棕发妞怎么样?
How was that brunette?
肯定玩得挺欢 他可是一宿没回哟
Must have been a decent ride 'cause he never went home.
跟昨天同一件衬衫哦 Jimmy
Same shirt as yesterday, Jimmy.
你跟Beadie闹别扭了?
You catchin' hell from Beadie?
没有
No.
问问而已嘛
Just asking.
各位
Gentlemen.
凶杀案 巴蒂尔摩市中心
DOA, Central and Baltimore.
- 我两天前才出过任务 - 那老太婆?
- I took a call two days ago. - The old lady?
那又不是案子
That wasn't a call.
人家是自然死亡
That came back natural.
我宿醉着呢 Jay
Look. I'm hung over, Jay.
你们俩 一起去
Both of you. You're up.
妈妈 妈妈
Mommy. Mommy!
你好 Boris?
'Sup, Boris?
认识我么?
You know who I am?
我就是往你食堂卡里打钱的有钱叔叔
I'm that rich uncle been putting all that money in your canteen account.
在咱国家 我坐了四年牢
In my country, I was in jail four years.
在咱国家 这根本不算坐牢
In my country, this is not prison.
这算个屁
This is nothing.
我不需要钱
I don't need money.
我他妈不吃食堂
I don't need fucking canteen.
我不需要你
I don't need you.
凶手
Gangbanger?
- 杀人犯 - 行了 我明白了
- Gangbanger. - A'ight. I feel that.
我明白 可是
I feel that,but-
Avon说了
Avon over there
他相信你能给希腊人带个口信
he thinks you might be able to help get a message to the Greeks,
带给Vondas
to Vondas.
就算你不要我的钱
I mean, seeing as you don't need my money,
Vondas说不定想要呢
Vondas might be happy to have it.
他不肯见我 不见
He don't want to see me, he won't,
但他要是肯见
but if he do
那肯定是买你的面子
it's you that made it happen.
Sonny Mays迟到了
Sonny Mays is running late.
你能替他发言么?
Can you fill in as speaker?
该是袒露心迹的时候了 Bubs
It's time to share, Bubs.
不不 我不行 我今天不太舒服?
Nah, I don't think so. I'm not feeling so good today, you know?
作为你的监督人 我告诉你
As your sponsor, I'm telling you,
你总该跨出那一步
you got to step up for something.
不管往哪儿
I don't care what
无论是不是在这间屋子里
I don't careif it's in these rooms or not
止步不前是没有前途的
but there ain't no laying in the cut on this shit.
你总得要跨出那一步
You got to step up somewhere.
探长 能说几句吗?
Detective, can I get a word?
随便什么 嫌疑犯有消息吗?
Anything? Anything on the suspects?
那等你出来再说吧
Maybe on your way out, then.
后门开着
Back door was open.
看不出他是不是前门进来后门出去的
Can't tell if he ran through and out the rear.
他们
They.
除非他用猎枪狂扫不够
Unless the shooter put a bullet in her head
还要一枪爆头
for good measure after the shotgun.
我们两台街头监控被拆了
Also,two of our street cameras were disabled.
线给剪了
Wires ripped.
妈的 脑子倒没少动
Fuck. That's a whole lot of thinking
干出的事简直禽兽不如
for any motherfucker to do something like this.
怎么搞的?
How the fuck?
啊?
How?
他肯定是一直躲在柜子里
He must have been in that closet the whole time.
谁都没听到
No one heard shit.
给福利署打电话 快
Call DSS. Now.
后门有记者吗?
Any media out back?
开辆押送车过来
Bring a cage car around.
你怎么样?
Hey. How you doing?
我不知道我能帮什么忙
Look, I don't know what I can do to help.
我打这儿路过
I'm just tryin' to find my way.
看见那么多人 要不要帮你发饭票啥的
Seein' how crowded it is, maybe I could help you hand out tickets.
没事儿 Bubs 你不如帮忙端盘子吧?
That's fine, Bubs, really but wouldn't you rather serve?
发放午餐
Serve lunch.
就把吃的给别人?
You mean give the food to people?
这不挺好嘛?
Isn't that the best part?
不不 我干不了
Nah, I can't. No.
没事儿 来吧
All right. Come on.
有人帮忙我们总是需要的
We can always use an extra set of hands.
他摔倒在这儿
He fell out.
可能是吸毒过量致死
Last bottle of smoke probably did him in.
另一个醉鬼发现的 把我叫过来
Another drunk found him,pulled me off post.
到现场10点07分
10-7 when I arrived.
- 给鉴证科打电话了? - 说要等两三小时呢
- You call for a crime lab? - The wait's two to three hours.
一天他妈不如一天
Shit gets worse every day.
Jimmy?
你没事吧?
You OK?
去弄杯咖啡
Go get yourself a coffee
填完表 接着巡逻吧
do your paperwork, get back on the street.
交给我们就行
We got it from here.
反正我们也得等着
We're gonna wait on them anyway.
去吧
Go ahead.
谢了
Thanks.
别让这家伙溜了
Don't let this guy go anywhere.
我有东西忘车里了
I forgot something in the car.
带张报纸来看看吧?
Bring the paper in, will you?
有得好等了
We're gonna be here a while.
Hey.
现在喝早了点吧?
Little early for that, ain't it?
你丫干啥呢?
What the fuck you doing?
看着门 Bunk
Just watch the door, Bunk.
靠
Shit.
喂喂 Jimmy
Come on, Jimmy.
你正常点好嘛
Get a fuckin' grip.
Jimmy
Jimmy.
你发失心疯了怎么的?
Have you lost your fucking mind?
老天啊 你个死变态
Oh,Jesus Christ, you sick fuck.
巴的尓摩有个连环杀手
There's a serial killer in Baltimore.
专杀无力还手之人
He preys on the weakest among us.
必须将他绳之以法
He needs to be caught.
我走了
I'm going.
我可不趟这浑水
I don't want a part of this.